and you'll notice that sometimes people
explicitly nuke things from that list
because they don't want to
explicitly um point the bug Hunters at
these types of wones but they also want
to be able to take it in case it happens
because it's a it's a risk right it's a
you know a risk of some sort so bug
Bounty sometimes is a game and you have
to figure out how to play the
[Music]
game
[Applause]
[Music]
hey guys real quick I just wanted to do
a shout out to the hacker content team
uh they've been doing an awesome job
with us recently helping with the social
media management side and uh sort of
taking the load off of me so I can focus
on delivering awesome content for you
guys um so if you think your
organization as well could benefit from
some hacker oriented social media
management help then hacker content is
the number one place to get it um and I
highly recommend them so head over to
hacker content.com to send in an inquiry
uh and if you mention the podcast when
you do you'll get your first month of
social media management stuff free um so
yeah check that out all right back to
the Pod what's up Jason welcome to the
Pod man hey thanks for having me guys
it's good to be back of course yeah it
thanks for coming back on you're I think
I want to say you know ngly I think has
made a couple of appearances but I think
you're our our first two time solo guest
oh that's awesome that's a a good title
you have the honor my good sir um dude
this is looking like a pretty packed
document um where do we start where do
we start where do we start well recently
you actually switched over to full-time
working for yourself right yes I did
yeah that was that was what a couple
months ago yeah two and a half months
ago about three two and a half three
months ago yeah nice man H how's that
been going it's been going great so I um
you know like I was at a place and I've
always worked for other people my whole
life and and I've always felt like uh
you know I've worked with great teams
and stuff like that but you know when I
started doing the training last year um
it just became more and more apparent
that hey I could probably do this for
myself and you know my friends have been
pushing me to start my own consultancy
for a long time like Dan Dan misler and
like um you know Clint Gibler like those
guys have always just been like dude you
should have your own consultant like
there's no reason you should be working
for anybody else and so I finally took
their advice and so I started um Arcanum
information security which if you're a
fantasy nerd um it comes from the book
Name of the Wind Arcanum is the um it's
kind of the art of magic in that book
the P the Patrick rothic books I love
the I love the logo book yeah it's great
series of books what it called again
it's called The Name of the Wind is the
first book yeah of the wind all right
that's interesting I I I love the logo
you have for this for this
it's super it's super cool and I guess
it fits with that whole sort of dark
magic uh naming convention there that's
that's great and and so you're you've
been doing you know full-time that in
content creation and you've been running
the uh the the BG bounty hunters
methodology classes those have been I've
just seen so much good feedback for
those classes man all over my Twitter
feed yeah it's uh it's been great um so
you know I started those solo and then
now they're attached to the company and
we do Consulting and we're having a
whole bunch of other classes come out
this year so um but but yeah I mean the
bug Hunters methodology course has
surpassed even my wildest expectations
and the feedback has been fantastic from
students just uh you know like I I mean
I knew because I you know was a public
talk for a long time and I knew that
there was a lot of good response to it
um but the community around it the uh
the Discord the contributions from the
students I mean we have people dropping
scripts in there all the time to do cool
things um and just every class is also
different too like different uh
different student questions come up and
so like we go off on these awesome
tangents and since they're recorded you
just get like a lot of value out of uh
out of the course we've had guests come
on to do like small little like sections
it's been amazing I I sincerely enjoy
teaching this this course one of one of
my one of my favorite things you know
with with having sort of a a Content
community of sorts is when you are
talking about a specific subject or
something like that and then someone
from the community just drops something
in the Discord or something like that
that just blows your mind and it's like
so well developed and and not only you
know are they clearly understanding the
content that you're talking about but
then they've taken it a step further and
actually implemented it or exploited
something with it it's just the best
feeling ever it is when people find a
bug in the Discord I am like doing a
happy dance all the time like I'm just
like yes go everybody know yeah man yeah
you guys have uh you guys have JD in
your Discord xss Doom who's been he's
smart as F and his story is also amazing
so yeah dude I I was just talking to him
the other day he's awesome and he he's
been explaining some of the bugs that we
were talking and actually that's exactly
who I was thinking of which is hilarious
that's funny are good buddies yeah yeah
yeah that's great dude yeah so I'm
always blown away when I see the the
stuff that's going on in the Discord
because there's I mean I always feel
like there's no bugs and so when I see
people like posting all these bugs all
the time I'm like okay there's a lot of
bugs
there's bugs it just takes eyeballs
right it takes it takes different
perspectives and eyeballs yeah it sure
does and uh yeah so I guess bringing
back around to the the the bug Hunters
methodology piece this piece of content
super legendary you know I remember
reading this one I was just just getting
started in in bug Bounty and one of the
cool things that that really a you know
makes this one of the top pieces of
material in the industry is the fact
that you're constantly updating it so um
let me ask man what what kind of stuff
has been sneaking in there you don't
have to give us like you know the sauce
from like your you know you know now
very much deservedly paid course but uh
maybe maybe give us just a little hint
of what kind of stuff is is in this
latest uh you know evolution of of the
the talk yeah so um okay so the new
stuff this cohort right so I update the
class between each cohort um which is
usually I do a cohort every quarter
right so I'm not teaching the class all
the time it's not on demand video
anything like that so uh but for this
cohort we push really hard on a
JavaScript analysis section um because
we had some before but I was you know
like I was talking to a lot of the
students from the last cohort and it
there is this difference between like
pent testers and security Auditors who
are a little bit younger and a little
bit older and um and it's nothing to do
with like skill or age or anything like
that really but what it has to do with
like kind of the web you grew up in
right a lot of the methodologies for
testing websites are um and a lot of the
training out there is based around first
of all like you know um the structure of
the data being passed in you know
parameter value format and then um and
then you know pretty much like websites
where resources were statically linked
and stuff like that and that is not how
the modern web works right the modern
web is uh single page applications heavy
JavaScript everything is in that
JavaScript for functionality site
sometimes La loaded you know resources
and then you have you know now you have
Cloud protections protecting you know
every site and um and so there was this
kind of Gap that I wanted to help those
people who grew up in the old version of
kind of the web get to the new version
and I took inspiration from you guys too
you you've been talking a lot about
JavaScript bugs in the last like six
episodes right and so the thing I
thought there was a gap for is just that
there is is is an understanding for web
pen testers and hunters and so I started
at the beginning I'm like okay first how
do you find JavaScript both inline and
files right okay so what are the new
JavaScript Frameworks do like let's talk
about them let's talk about the hurdles
that they present for testers right so
lazy loading highly minified JavaScript
okay how do we overcome those right okay
how do we get the lazy loaded
application um you know to either show
up in our proxy or you know raw we can
get to the files or something like that
and then is there any way that we can
deal with minification and Aus of
JavaScript and what are we looking for
in the JavaScript specifically and so I
built out a whole section around that
and um I I like scoured the internet for
the best de offia skaters and the best
tools um and like I even built like
ghetto strings analysis cheat sheets um
you know like stuff you can just control
F4 and then I you know I talked about
you know putting JavaScript into you
know vs code and building rejects like
more advanced rejects for finding stuff
that you want to look for in files um I
talked about obviously you know if you
have raw JavaScript I talked about um
using things like Gap and um and JS
Loose by Tom Nom Nom I talked about that
um you know and how pathing is so weird
in JavaScript how you can build paths
you know dynamically and so you can miss
them if you're not looking right or
you're not building them or constructing
them right so those are the types of
things I talk about in the JavaScript
section and it was fantastically
received like amazing um so that was
that section um and then I did a cheat
sheet for all of the JavaScript
front-end engines and what's you know
what were uh you know what are the
common vulnerable yeah what are the
common what are the common issues with
that framework how does it handle
certain special characters where um
where are the main app files hosted
where is the database connection string
hosted so in case there's some kind of
Access Control vulnerability set up on
those files and then you know like the
bigger the biggest one being like you
know dangerous to set in HTML or
something like that like how that leads
to you know can lead to issues and so um
I started to build those cheat sheets
for the students too to have um to take
home yeah do how often do you find that
while you're writing these that it's
it's more of like a like a relearning
process for yourself more than like a
writing for everybody else because I
find when I do this sort of writing I
I'm like I'll I'll write something and
I'll be like actually is that true and
then I'll go back and I'll check it and
I find myself going down a big rabbit
hole where I'm learning a ton more about
that and then I Circle back and and I
write that down um do you find that that
is the case a lot 100% um in fact some
of the stuff I do in the class I know
that I have a big big blind spot for
certain sections of tech and I so I put
it in the syllabus and I promise it to
the students and then that forces me to
create the content and be an expert on
it just be like and it's like it's like
this ADHD that I do all the time and
it's like okay now it's out there and
they're expecting J hadex level content
from you in this section so you better
kill it and I'm like okay cool like
let's go that's such a hack because I
feel like a lot of people the
traditional wisdom is like don't post
about your goals until you've achieved
them or something like that cuz it like
steals the dopamine or something like
that from you and you like get the
dopamine ahead of time or I don't know
I've heard that before but I'm like
total opposite of that I'm like let's
you know promise it and then force
yourself to Li on it I feel like that's
such a good way to motivate yourself
yeah worked really well for me there's
this there's this blog that I love
called the weight but y it's written by
this guy Tim Urban and he uh he did a
TED talk about like procrastination and
one of the things that he talks about is
this concept of like a chaos monkey that
lives in your brain and he only really
comes out if there's like fear of
embarrassment or really strict deadlines
oh my go and that is like exactly how I
operate which is that there's this chaos
monkey that never comes out until like
I've I've set some sort of really bad
parameter or or like guard rail in place
that if I hit it it's going to be a
disaster and then I'll actually get the
thing done yeah yeah no dude yeah I
think that that's good I was just going
to say you know with regards to I can't
relate as much to the to the ADHD you
know approach to things but I can
definitely say that like trying to
motivate yourself to accomplish
monumentally huge tasks is you
definitely need some hacks for that if
you're going to do it on a regular basis
and I'm really impressed that you went
through and actually started working and
you know got so far in this cheat sheet
because that requires so much Dev as
well man like when I hear about you
saying like ah you know I'm going to
take all these Frameworks and like
figure out how all of the you know
special characters are handled in the
parsing and that sort of thing it's like
oh my gosh that hurts but really when
you when you get through that you have
such a better understanding of where
that data lives for each one of these
individual you know framework types that
are getting so common and I think you
know with with that you can really use
that to write better Rejects and write
tools that will better parse those JS
files to pull out the the paths Etc
which which is really valuable yeah you
know one thing I noticed doing um doing
the cheat sheets specifically was that
um was that there was this common thing
around all of kind of the new Frameworks
uh whether they're JavaScript or not and
it's that that you cannot use the
default functions to protect uh you know
to do input en coding or output uh or
output en coding or input validation on
certain sections of the app like it just
doesn't work right and like a lot not a
lot of people think of this like this
right so it's like it's like okay let's
say you're building a web hook right
like you know to integrate with another
site right well it's it's very hard to
implement those functions across like an
integration piece of your application
right and so like people just don't do
it they're like they have to you know
somehow take special characters of
certain sorts into the integration back
end and hook it up via web hook and then
um so so there's like common places and
I've put them in a section um that I
call heat mapping um where like it's
just really hard to integrate those
protections and so I say check those
first right because like you know
there's bound to be bugs there so yeah
yeah
absolutely so moving a little bit away
from the JavaScript stuff because we we
may have bored our users over the P
listeners over the past weeks on
JavaScript stuff cuz I don't know I've
just been loving that [__] lately um but
you know the buck bounty hunters
methodology has sort of evolved a little
bit like you mentioned and now there's
there's a bunch of different aspects of
it including red team related stuff that
I think you've broken out uh a little
bit um and then we like we were talking
about right before we went live there's
this aspect of some of these more red
team techniques sort of sneaking their
way into bug bounties nowadays um so you
want to talk a little bit about that
yeah so the like I try to keep the class
at two days and um and so what happened
was I had a whole bunch of red team
content in there from my last year and a
half of like diving head first into
modern red teaming and so I had to spin
it out um and I I still give it right
now in this in the format it's into the
students as like an extra section after
time is over for the two days but uh you
know that section is a lot more for uh
you know hardcore red teamer it's all my
tips and tricks and so we we talk a lot
about things like you know what is the
best Stage zero uh C2 right so like um
we use you know we use Nim plant right
as our stage zero U you know implant and
then we have a stage two implant and
then um we talk about like modern
techniques for can you define those for
me I'm I'm not as familiar with yeah I'm
not familiar with it either yeah okay so
there is this whole community of
security right I mean like we're very
used to bug Bounty and ABC that's where
I lived for many years but when I
started testing I was a red teamer and
and back then red teaming meant
Metasploit you guys know about metas
sploit right yeah yeah yeah of course
yeah yeah yeah absolutely so I mean so
like metas sploit was kind of our first
like and Cobalt strike were two of our
first c2s command and control servers
right and so the idea is you know in red
teaming you get initial access um and
you can get inial access access through
a whole bunch of ways you can fish
somebody um which you know you can um
fish them for credentials or you can
fish them to have them open a file and
actually get a shell on their box um and
so back in the day you know like this
wasn't super hard like red teaming like
you could you could win on a very simple
technique of sending a VBA macro or
something to somebody and them opening
it and then you were you were good but
modern red teaming is much more complex
because people have EDR software on
their box um there's way more email
filtering um there's just a ton of stuff
uh that is meant to stop you know actual
adversaries of which if you are a red
teamer you're trying to emulate like an
adversary so um so you know the first
thing you have to decide on when you're
when you're building your red team
practice is kind of your implant which
is like once you exploit someone um how
are you going to gain control over
memory um on their box and then pivot
from there and then make sure that if
some security software or a reboot
happens that you can regain your
connection and that's the goal of what a
C2 server is as a command and control
server right and so um so you have to
choose and there's hundreds of C2
servers open source closed Source paid
not paid um and so we talk about the
decisions that I made in building my red
team infrastructure over the past year
and a half and so um one of the things
we used you know as a stage zero implant
was nant which is the Nim programming
language which is harder for edrs to
parse and basically um report on and so
implant was our stage zero but as far as
like a usability um tool like you can
build the implant and then a user you
know you fish them or they click on a
file or something like that and then you
have control over their box as far as
usability an implant leaves a little bit
to desired so then you have a stage uh
instead of a stage zero you have a stage
one which is a better like more modern
framework where I can log into a web
guey and kind of control somebody's
computer and so you know we use a
different C2 after an implant and and
how do you how are you sneaking that so
okay so let me get this because this is
this is bringing me back to my
Consulting days a little bit man I
wasn't red team stuff but like I was
doing pentesting stuff and we absolutely
were using Cobalt on basis and that sort
of thing the the go-to approach I guess
back then was you know having some sort
of um obfuscation tool that would or or
writing something custom yourself to get
the connection back to Cobalt but so you
know you land on the machine with with
uh Nim plant and then you know you're
escalating you're using a different um I
guess sort of C2 to have more
interactive interact ability of sorts
and how are you sneaking that second
payload past whatever restrictions are
on the
device yeah usually dlll side loing is
the main okay um is the main thing um so
we we went from Nim plant as stage one
C2 to Sharp C2 as our stage two and so
you can Sid load in an executable
straight into memory you can sideload in
a dll you can run custom Powershell you
can run custom shell script you know
like you if you're on a Linux box um the
only problem with sharp C2 was that it
it ended up on some um like antivirus uh
list and they had basically blacklisted
the function names in the implants yeah
and so you have to do this intermediate
step using this tool called confuser ex
which will statically rename all of the
function names to different words and
then you can get you can bypass most EDR
these days it's so it's so funny I that
was that was the case back in the day as
well when I was doing it and you just go
in there and you like open it up and
just change the name a little bit and
then you know it's crazy man the the the
stuff that they're detecting off of for
that it's
really go I was gonna say it's always
super interesting how there's like these
huge Suites of tools that like exist for
every sort of section within security
like I haven't heard of this any of
these except for metas point and Cobalt
strike and it's just you know it's
really interesting to hear about all
these very specific sort of tools that
exist for these specific problems that
are common but like in bug Bing we never
have to deal with this like the we don't
function names in an executable being
detected by antiv virus is just not
something that's ever even on our radar
no yeah it is it is very much a
discipline that um could consume your
whole brain honestly and and I wouldn't
even consider myself an expert in it
right uh but I I knew enough to to get
going and so um yeah so in the red team
section we basically spun it out into
its own course now um and one of the
things that like I see you know I saw as
like actually a defender or I guess you
and if you want to call me Defender like
a ciso right um during my life was that
um what you get in a red team or a
pentest report these days is good it's
it's valuable there's you know often
very good findings in there but it
doesn't actually mimic what real
adversaries are doing and the lattice of
or the like the order of operations they
go through to try to breach you um which
has a lot to do with just buying creds
on the dark web and the underground
which Joel and or which Jus and I were
talking about before the show so um you
know if we want to dive in we can yeah
no 100% and that's what I was going to
ask you was like I I'm wondering you
know we talked about some of this red
teaming stuff how can we apply those
things that we've learned from Red
teaming to bug bounty in a way that
they're going to get accepted yeah yeah
so so one of the things is is like kind
of threat Intel based findings right and
there are couple Hunters that exist out
there that have been doing this for a
long time um but it's not really a
talked about topic I would say a ton and
this is the idea of finding working
domain credentials on the dark web and
submitting them as a bug Bounty report
and so in my experience it's about 5050
so um the first thing is you have to
make sure that the cred is actually
working right so it's a domain
credential you're able to get access to
somebody's domain account um possibly
through a VPN concentrator a piece of it
infrastructure Hardware or just into
their Microsoft Azure account or
something like that as a um you know as
kind of like a to prove that you have
data um that's private and access that
is you know um a big deal and so uh and
so you have things like have I been
pwned and then some like middling stuff
like dehashed which is a service that is
like have I been pwned but um basically
gives you the actual passwords um and
that would be like what I call level one
threat inel data and is most often
already patched by the time it gets to
those services like have I been pwned
and dehashed I mean not patched but the
credentials have been changed
the cookies have been rolled all that
kind of stuff already so it's not really
going to be that useful for you but
they're like a level two three and four
of how deep you get into the dark web
Forum ecosystem and more these days the
telegram ecosystem of people selling
credentials um that are fresh and so
like five out of my last six red team
engagements I have got in from Gathering
these credentials from Telegram and
Discord channels of actual threat actors
dude that's not so and and are you
buying the credentials just the
credentials you need in that scenario or
do you end up having to like drop a
grand on like some sort of you know big
giant list of
credentials so uh it depends on how the
seller sells them right so uh basically
what happens is these adversaries are
career Fishers or career um you know
operators of M of cred Steeler mware so
like red line or something like that is
a very common one that people get hit
with and so they're not actively
targeting a company they're targeting
large swaths of people in their
campaigns and then they sell the result
of their campaigns and in order to prove
to the community that the campaign is uh
fresh and um and has good data in it
they give what's called a Steeler log
sample in the telegrams and so you can
parse those and look for your company or
uh your bug Bounty targets um domain
inside of the Steeler log um samples and
then if you see them you can download
them and grab the creds out of those
samples are these like a like a
standardized format that they're dumping
these in in in in telegram or you just
kind of grepping through and just see
like you know anything that says you
know uber.com you know or whatever it's
it's not standardized all the time
because every different info stealer
malware uh formats the output of what
they take from your machine differently
so like you know sometimes there's a
passwords file uh sometimes there's like
you know it's embedded like three
folders deep and not called passwords
the format different and how they pull
it from the browser but when you buy the
packs I think your original question was
if if you can go to the Forum ecosystem
and find a cred for let's say we're
doing Uber right or something like that
right like um so you can yeah you can
look for at uber.com and some of the
form ecosystems and immediately buy
those and you can buy them for as cheap
as $10 um for a cred um now there is no
warranty on the forums as to if that's
going to be um valid or fresh um but you
know that is you know a lot of times
what happens what about like what about
like tofa in that scenario yeah so a lot
of times you'll get tofa but what
happens with these cred stealer malware
like Redline they don't just steal your
creds they steal your cookies too which
uh because they're system level malware
right so they steal your cookies right
out of chrome right out of Brave and so
if I can find the domain in the cred um
on the Forum or either in an info
stealer uh I know that they'll have the
cookie too somewhere um for the browser
and so then I can grab the cookie and
just inject it and walk in um and so
that is that is the beauty of and the
beauty and the the hate of kind of the
underground right is like they're
they're starting to sell more than just
cookies um I mean they dump so much
stuff with the cred Steeler malware now
it's it's pretty insane but um but yeah
so and then there's there's other people
who sell large packs and you look at the
um the preview and those can be
thousands of dollars um and so it just
depends on you know if I'm on a red team
engagement how much did they pay me for
the red team engagement how much am I
willing to invest in success right uh um
there's also some legality around it too
like buying stuff off the dark I was
going to ask about that I mean is there
like some is there legal considerations
or I don't know maybe even ethical
considerations with like all right I'm
I'm sort of funding this this industry
Andor giving money to Career criminals
you know yeah no it's it's been a topic
of debate on on Twitter I think um so
when we go into a red team engagement we
talk to our client about this right it's
not like we just do this off the bat and
we're like hey these are your these are
your credentials and your employees so
you can give us explicit access to
access um you know the Steeler log data
um and we ask them if they would like us
to purchase it or get an intermediary to
purchase it so that's one conversation
you have to have um the other one is
usually we don't have to have a
conversation with them and in a bug
bounty hunt too is if they're already
being disclosed in the preview that's
free right so if you find a cred in the
preview that's free that's already on
the public internet basically um and so
those we just we tend to just grab and
tell them about and use them in the
operation or report to the bug Downy so
are you indexing them at all or is it
just sort of Case by case because i'
I've had some discussions and I have a
little bit of a pipe dream at some point
where I'd like to download like
basically every public breach dump that
I can and there are some tools out there
um one that I found that's pretty good
that's by um sense post it's called fra
it's designed
for um you know breach data um and
searching it in like an efficient way
but do you do any of that with the data
that you're buying or do you do that any
P like passively for other engagements
and stuff or yeah so I I cheat a little
bit so when I was at when I was at bobot
building the red team um
capabilities um I bought a company like
I did a ton of research into companies
that did this already right they indexed
and they crawled and they could get to
level that I didn't want to put in the
work to do right like you have to have
sock puppet accounts sometimes to get to
this level of data like you have to be
very careful about your opsac and so uh
there are several companies that are at
this like level three cred intelligence
exposure level and so I bought flare
when um I was at uh when I was at butto
and so I found them to be the best and
so I used them in my red team Ops and
then luckily when I left they were like
hey we really enjoyed that relationship
would you like to come be part of our
company and so like full disclosure I'm
like shill yeah I'm not Shilling the
flare because because I work I like work
there parttime I'm Shilling them because
they're [__] amazing so um I love
that order you know of like I love the
product I use the product and now I work
for the product well I mean like it's
it's like you guys with kaido right like
I mean you know it's it's amazing like
um yeah so uh yeah so flare has a datab
base um and like a very Sim style
dashboard to look up all the D all the
dark web creds and grab them and so I I
used flare pretty much exclusively but
you know it is it is a product that you
have to buy and so in the course I talk
about some um repos that have lists of
all of the underground telegram channels
all of the underground forums and a
whole bunch of Torance for the latest um
public breaches so that you can build
your own and so um let's see we can give
that to the listeners for free let's see
here that'd be great if you could you
drop in the in the Discord or in the the
Google Doc that'd be really cool yeah
absolutely so one is um one is let's see
here you guys are having me pull up my
notes my bad
yeah it's it's a lot of work to get all
that that you know data all cleaned as
well so It's Tricky and I I wonder you
know I I imagine that service has got to
be pretty expensive I have I've never
seen it but so I don't think they were
of doing it but me and a couple of other
like red team consultancies saw like
they were originally marketing towards
CTI teams right and businesses but then
I think me and a couple of other very
forward-thinking red teaming companies
came to them and were like well yo we
would pay less than kind of what your
Enterprise offering was but you know
we'd use this in our red team
engagements do you have a model for that
and I think what was really cool was
that most CTI companies would be like no
F off like that's not something we want
to do and Flair was like yeah sure let's
figure it out and so there is like a
like a like a pentest shop SL R team
shop package that flare does oh really
still it's still not you know like
trivial but it is less than you know
kind of an Enterprise deployment so does
do they have their their stuff public
for the prices on that I want to look it
up right now I am I am very very new and
I am only part-time so I'm still
learning okay got we'll have to go we'll
have to go sus that and we'll link it
down in the description afterwards but I
could definitely see I could definitely
see that being a worthwhile investment
and I have heard of some bringing this
back to bug Bounty I have heard of some
people in the community absolutely
crushing it with the credential thing
like I don't know man that feels a
little bit it feels a little bit meh to
me from from a bounty perspective but
like you know like you were saying
before the call if you at the end of the
day bug Bounty can be reduced down to PC
or GTFO and if at the end of the day
you're logging in and you're leaking
data that's bad and that needs to be
fixed
yeah I think from a a customer point of
view also you I mean like I think that
it's something I talk about in the class
I ranted on a lot this weekend was um
you have to think about it from a
customer point of view too right so like
let's say that a Bug Hunter comes to you
and says that they have a working domain
credit and they and domain credentials
they've walked into your VPN right and
you didn't explicitly put that stuff out
of scope what are you going to do are
you going to out of scope that dude who
could blog about it and say I got into
you know Uber and like just like an no
you're not you're going to pay the P1
and be like cool thanks for the report
Nei you're going to decide that's
something you want to continue to do and
put it in scope it's going to be
something that's a gray area you're
still not going to put it in scope and
maybe accept it you know a piece by
piece or you're going to take it
explicitly out of scope um for the
Bounty and so you know when bug bounty
hunt or bug Bounty platforms like hacker
one and Bug Crow Integrity um you know
they start a bounty with people these
are the type of things that they talk
about in the kickoff calls like do you
want creds coming in do you care about
creds that are leaked on GitHub you know
and so they have a very defined list of
out of scope things and you'll notice
that sometimes people explicitly nuke
things from that list because they don't
want to
explicitly um point the bug Hunters at
these types of wones but they also want
to be able to take it in case it happens
because it's a it's a risk right it's a
you know a risk of some sort so bug
Bounty sometimes is a game and you have
to figure out how to play the game yeah
yeah that there's such a Sweet Spot
there of like it's not in the out of
scope so they accept it but it's not in
the in scope so that they incentivize
looking for it and and that if you can
find that margin of stuff that's not
obvious to other Hunters but you know
the client is vulnerable too and willing
to pay for that's some money right there
yeah I mean you're like green you're
Greenfield hunting at that point right
so yeah I know of at least three Hunters
who do this kind of cred cred Intel
hunting like like almost exclusively
and they don't talk about it very much
yeah I wonder why I wonder why they
don't talk about it very much yeah I
think most a lot of programs don't count
credential stuffing as like a valid B
and even like even if it is like one set
of creds I think a lot of programs will
say well this there's not a systemic
issue here this is like at most some
sort of like misconfiguration or a gap
or like a lapse in sort of like the
external monitoring side more than like
there's nothing to fix right there's no
code change or anything like that um so
much as like maybe a policy change and
so I think a lot of programs just say
you know thanks for letting us know but
you know we're not going to pay for you
know one set of creds um but I guess it
it really depends on like if you can do
like if you could show like a lot of
impact then I think depending on the
program some will accept and some won't
so if you find a domain credential and
you're working against some Modern
organization that has a like a VPN login
and you know the creds work on a VPN
login because you know they're tied up
to the Azure you know the Azure
authentication system then I found most
people are like yeah we we we'll pay for
that um it really also depends on the
history of security of the company
itself I found so companies that have
been breached by credentials being
leaked online really [__] care about
it right and mentioning Uber here I
don't
yeah and then companies who are who have
never had a breach um via this method
they don't care and and you know what I
mean I think that that's fair I I also
think that they haven't been through
that pain and understand it and I think
that you know if they do get hit with it
eventually guess what's going in scope
and guess like I've seen I mean I don't
want to leak any like anything crazy but
there are at least two programs either
existing right now or being designed
right now for specifically thread Intel
data in three of the bounty platforms or
so there's there's two and two of the
bounty platforms right now um and so
this is about to be a thing like this is
about to be a new skill set that maybe
we do have to develop um and some people
have been doing it for a while and other
people will have to figure it out so
dang man super cool that's gonna be
intense get get your get your telegram
scraper scripts ready because uh that's
gonna be that's definitely going to be
the direction that the the industry is
moving in I think um so I guess well
we'll leave that that topic there and I
want to move into um some of the bug
bounty hunting you've been doing lately
and I've seen you hitting FIS and I've
heard from other hackers that FIS is a
great Target can you give me the rundown
of that yeah so uh I mean really was
inspired by you guys I think um doing
the the Discord Community like the kind
of like um access only or paid only
version of the Discord Community yeah
and you know what I'm good at is like
I'm good at a lot of things but I'm
really good at Recon I'm you know I I
don't have any qualms in like saying
that I'm you know like that is one of my
specialties and um and so my idea was
that as part of the Discord subscription
every month we would choose a target a
wides scope Target and I would kick off
doing recon um with you know like I have
all of the paid Services I subscribe to
them all um I'm doing all of the methods
in the presentation which are the extra
10 to 15% stuff that nobody else will do
um and I'm finding Apex domains that
nobody else has found um and so we did
FIS uh this last month it was our um
first or second target I believe um as
part of the Discord and so um a whole
bunch of hunters found bugs um I found
some bugs um you know Recon based bugs
basically but we also learned a lot
about Enterprise deployments of security
products and kind of um changing our
Recon methodology a little bit depending
on what was going on and we implemented
some really cool new stuff that went
directly into the class that students
had dropped in the channel for things
that had successfully found them hosts
and um yeah so we learned a lot
um one of the first things we learned
was about like an
aggressive uh an aggressive deployment
of you know a cloud you know protection
like aamai or um something like that
yeah for sure yeah and so what we found
was um you know when we were doing we
were doing recon for FIS um we were
getting 403 all over the place with um
the aamine cloud flare um basically
inline you know wafts and so uh what we
learned was there were whole swaths of
their sites um their websites which
eventually wanted to get to right um
were they just blacklisted VPS providers
like they blacklisted digital ocean they
blacklisted AWS their whole thinking was
that classic hey yeah hey if if you're
using this website you should be a user
only and you should be coming from a
residential IP Block it's not a bad idea
you know it's there's no reason why
these VPS should be actually hitting
your website yeah I mean unless you have
some kind of integration where uh you
know a partner of yours is coming off of
one of those things that's why it's a
little bit more dangerous with like
Amazon but they definitely blacklisted
the hell out of digital ocean for sure
um and so and so uh you know that's my
preferred VPS so I noticed right away I
was like why is this happening and you
know I'm working with a couple other
people doing the initial Recon and it's
like okay well they're they're
blacklisting anything but residential IP
addresses so then I had to take my whole
Recon like setup and move it to a Cali
box in a um you know in a virtual
machine on my home network right so that
I could hit a lot of these sites gez I
hope you got a strong internet
connection I hope you've got Jo you know
what was it 10 gigabit that was crazy
yeah so I mean I have good internet so
it was fine but then you run the risk of
um blacklisting your house if you if you
send attack traffic or if you send too
many requests in a row so it was it was
really trial and error and So eventually
what had to get to was using htpx to
pull down the data that we wanted we had
to like run from my house and we had to
rotate um user agent strings and we had
to bring it down to 15 threads no way
dude that's so much holy crap so it took
us it took us a week and a half to do a
full scan across all of their Apex
domains um and so that was just like the
the learnings that we've had and then we
we've moved into next month we're going
to do T-Mobile and um and they have some
of the same configuration so luckily we
learned these we learned these uh these
things early um and so that led us into
like these discussions of like okay well
like how can we do this without being
that ghetto right just like bringing it
back into my home and um and so we're
looking in right now into I just
finished my interview with them a week
and a half ago is bright data have you
guys ever heard of bright Data before
I've not heard of this no no okay so
bright data is a company that basically
is a u a proxy company for people who
want to do web scraping and so they have
sever different types of networks that
you can subscribe to and you basically
set up this proxy agent and then every
request you make through the proxy agent
um you set it up the same way you would
set up a socks proxy goes from a
different IP basically oh nice um it's
like that thing in Amazon what is it uh
uh the fire fireo whatever fire uses on
the back end I think it's like API
Gateway or something like that API
Gateway yeah so a lot of API Gateway
stuff has been even blacklisted um now
so bright data pays people to run their
agent on their local computer kind of
like we used to do folding at home and
stuff like that in that's sketchy man
this is Mega sketchy cuz there's a lot
of companies that this stuff for like
Instagram proxies that are as a service
or something like that like so um so I
just got approved and so uh to you have
to you have to take an interview with
them and uh and now I can proy all my
Recon scans through bright data's cons
um their residential proxies so these
are people's homes so for this kind of
protection FIS will not be able to block
me anymore um and they will be able to
they will like you know I am not I'm not
scanning them with like nuclei or
anything like that I am literally just
doing the same kind of work that
scrapers do so I want to pull back with
httpx I want to pull back the uh ASN
that it resolves to the title is really
important
um uh the fabon hash yeah uh I'm not
doing screenshotting in my first round
of Recon I usually do it like in my
second round but um yeah I mean mostly
I'm just pulling metadata about the site
um yeah to get us kicked off but yeah
that's uh that's a thing that we're
doing I think that's so funny man we
were like well this is super sketchy and
then Jason's like anyway I signed
up that's cool man and I and I think you
know it's it's a valid way to get around
it you know these poor people are going
to have aami bands on their houses but
that's what you get when you sign up for
bright data or whatever to be an agent
well I think that I think that rotation
happens every request right and so the
Network's big enough so that I don't
think that individuals will get banned
by the cloud proxies if we keep the
threads down I don't plan to blast like
you know like 6,000 threads or something
like that right hopefully they're
they're rate limiting that too from
their side uh because that you know
those those proxy end points are their
that's their thing so I imagine they do
something like that from that level but
it's definitely a creative way to get
around around the you know restrictions
that you run into the if API Gateway is
is out of the question yeah yeah for
sure so um so yeah that was some of the
stuff that kind of came out of that
shook out of that um we also realized
that they were um they were geoca or
locking um like regionalized domains so
like you know f. UK or f. JP or
something like that you couldn't get to
them without being from one of those so
we've started to build some um some
stuff that can get around that like some
you know mostly socks proxy just stuff
to get around that we don't have to do
the bright data stuff for that yeah get
some like little localized provider or
something like that been up a little VPS
over there exactly yeah some data center
and you know yeah yeah that makes that
makes sense no that that's good and
there's and this is the kind of thing we
talk about all the time on the pod which
is like if you go that extra mile to get
access to something that's really really
really annoying to get access to or
costs any amount of money at all um
there's so much less competition in
there from a bug Bounty perspective um
yeah and so getting access to
geolocation stuff getting access to or
even like attack getting targets I have
a mentee that I'm working with and I
told him you know you should attack
programs that you have access to from
your from your country that only you can
sign up for so he went after this
banking app and uh he's found a bunch of
really awesome bugs there and it's
because no one else has the you know
whatever government registration number
that that you need to sign up and
actually get an account on this thing
and uh and actually pop it so
geolocated stuff is huge I think that
this is part of um a discussion we have
in the class I have with the students
about going deep right there's a lot of
people including your guys you guys who
talk about going deep and like sometimes
don't talk about the application as we
like to call here getting intimate yeah
but but sometimes like people are like
just go deep and you're like what the
[__] does that mean like what do you
mean bro like you know like like what do
youan my hands yeah what do I do with my
hands like like give me like you know
and so so one of the things is you know
paid access to paid functions right so
like you know not many bug Hunters are
willing to pay for some of the pro
versions of the applications and get
access to the functionality that is you
know cost the money as an investment and
that can be super Green Field um
geolocation or places that you can only
access with certain types of data um so
one being like you said like maybe a a
regionalized drivers's license number
regionalized Social Security number
regionalized insurance number like
hitting those functions that that make
you have to that maybe things that
require kyc right like some bug hunt
will see kyc and just completely stop
and they'll be like cool not doing that
um you know yeah it's scary man it's
scary I I I I've put my social security
number into multiple websites for bug
hunting and it's like okay this is
probably not the best idea but also you
know the payoff can be huge and and it
it was funny a couple events back this
is probably two years ago go I was
talking to Ben and Ben had like signed
up for a credit card and opened a bank
at this account at this company and I
was like dude did you really like do all
that and he's like yeah man like you
know a lot of people do this for the
signing bonus and I you know I'm about
to pop like a 10K crit on this thing and
I'm like wow yeah that's much better
than the signing bonuses you get for
like opening a bank account somewhere
yeah I one of the other things we talk
about is like many companies will have a
developer program right and you get
extra access and early access to
Features right so you can join the
developer
you can you know depending on what type
of site it is there's you know reseller
programs that get access to whole
portions of the application that nobody
you know has seen before as a bug Bounty
Hunter so there's just all these
different ways to get extra
functionality to hack so we talk a lot
about that in in the course so I I think
I think using your own position whatever
it is using your position as an American
using your uh you know position as a
developer using your position as um this
makes me think of that episode with with
mayonnaise how he used his understanding
of the digital marketing industry to
apply that to his hacking and how how
much success he got out of that with the
Yahoo program um so you know each one of
us has our own eyes and we talk about
that all the time on the podcast and and
through bugb media but you you kind of
got to ask yourself when you're picking
a Target what am I what do I have
advantage on you know that somebody else
doesn't have and how do I apply that to
these targets these list of targets that
I've got to pick one that I have the
best chance of popping um yeah it's a
big thing right there yeah so I mean
there's a whole bunch of other stuff in
the dock I mean I know we're running
pretty log but um no no we are we are
dude what I want to see next what I want
to see next is these new Recon
techniques because you like this one
says reverse DeMark and I had not seen
this before so hit me with that all
right okay so like some of these are are
really like like new and you know kind
of exclusive to the course but I love
you guys so I I will drop them in the PO
on okay all right well you don't have to
go into too much detail but yeah okay so
the first one is reverse DNS right and
so the the idea of the idea of of
forward DNS lookup right like is is you
know very used to you know it's like an
interview question we get in Tech you
know is like how does DNS work right
like when you go to google.com what
happens right but um a lot of times
right now uh what you can do is you can
ask the reverse question of um you know
what what domains lie in this IP address
and if they have pointer records um you
can find out what do Apex domains live
on and subdomains live on certain IP
addresses and so this can be really
useful if you're looking at if you have
the IP address of you know an ASN for a
target of yours right so you know their
autonomous system numbers you know they
own this IP space and you can run
pointer record lookups on them so
there's there's one tool that does this
yes this is yeah this is the tool we us
yeah hack rev DNS does this right so
hack rev DNS does this um and then a
whole bunch of other websites can do
this for you through their guey right um
and so this is one technique that is
kind of wellknown but it works really
well it works Works amazing um to find
subdomains that are kind of hidden in
these pointer records and so that's
that's a cool thing to find the the more
newer kind of edge case is that um is
that you know there's a lot of companies
like security trails and um netlist and
these companies that are spiders of
infrastructure on the internet like
showon and things like that right and so
these companies who sell you know to me
it's Recon data to other people I don't
know what they do with it but to me it's
data absolutely Recon data yeah yeah um
so for these companies that sell that
they all have different um inies that
they plan and so one is uh who is XML
API is a pretty well-known one um it's a
website that you can go to and they are
for pay and so I you know I have to
invest a little bit into doing this
technique but what they had the ability
to do is a reverse name server lookup
and so what we found with FIS was that
they're using aami as their name server
fronting right and so what you can do is
they have like six six name servers if
you just dig them right for their name
servers and you're like cool these are
the aami name servers that they're using
well through is who is XML API and one
of the search um and one of the API uh
queries you can do with them is you can
say what other servers use this name
server and you would be surprised about
the records that come back it's usually
around 6,000 to 8,000 hosts come back
using an aami yeah using an aami fronted
name server but with some simple grep
for knowing your customers like you know
for FIS I look for FIS and some of their
other Apex domains using some simple GP
through there we found some Apex domains
that we did not find anywhere else like
literally like 12 Apex domains that
belong to FIS that were being used that
no other Hunter had found by using this
query yeah so we had green we had green
field and then you run those through
subdomain Discovery right and then um
yeah and so that was you know that
reverse DNS technique was was Val that's
that's something that I've I've thought
of before but I would have thought was
just too bloated like you know
especially in modern Cloud
infrastructure I'm impressed that you
even rent it against Akamai related
stuff because I would you know maybe I
would say if we had if this a company
had their own you know name servers that
they have you know that they're or
something like that yeah yeah it works
great for that but even on I mean it's
all it's all an amount of so I call some
of these methods in the later part of
the of the classes I call them l methods
like if you think in like if you're an
audio file right and you think about
audio sometimes you know some kind some
types of audio are lossy right and they
require you know a lot of work to um you
know get gold out of them but sometimes
they pay off a lot and so they're all on
the course right and so um this one is
uh this one you know with some simple
grepping honestly for FIS or Fidelity or
whatever we found some amazing stuff um
when you said audio file I just I'm just
seeing that's a very common term I know
I know but I'm not an audio file no no
no so I'm seeing myself as like a MP
three or whatever like I'm like if I'm
an audio file what you that's what the
audio files you know here on the podcast
be are like what is wrong with you
Justin no no like like a person who's
really into who's really into like the
Fidelity of
audio I'm sure I'm sure Joel knows
exactly what Loi you know means We Just
Gotta Throw Some terms out yeah yeah
yeah um so that so those are the two
reverse DNS methods um and then I I put
in the doc uh reverse DeMark and this
was one that um xnl hacker um uh gave to
me and so y dude xnl is amazing uh I
don't know if you guys are gonna have
him on your show at some point but he's
fantastic to yeah for sure okay I'll
I'll put in a good word he's he's a
homie so um uh so uh reverse T mark is
you know another one of these reverse
type um you know lookups and so
basically there's a few websites which
categorize all the Demar records on the
entire internet they have spiders that
go off and grab Demar records and um and
so you can just look at a company and
their Demar record and see what other uh
what other domains those are applied to
and we found some amazing Apex domains
from that and the same thing happens
with CSP so you can look at a CSP po
policy there's several websites out
there that you can do a reverse lookup
on a CSP policy um for a domain to see
if it matches one one to one and then
you can find Apex domains or subdomains
using using that method so those are
three of the newer ones that we've been
running I I'm looking here at the DeMark
policy okay I see I see where the where
the domain is defined here yeah that's
something that I that I hadn't really
thought of but man these these sort of
Fringe techniques dude you you got you
got to really just automate them and
then blast them all out there you know
because there could be some crazy stuff
that comes back from you know reverse
DeMark and and uh and that's the one
thing you need to get access to
especially like you said things that
give you access to Apex domains and then
now you've identified a new Apex domain
and then you have you know a clear CL or
clear set you know approach
to expanding your scope once you have
that that Apex level domain um so that's
really valuable the CSP thing I've seen
many times before yeah yeah I mean
Corbin actually talked about it on
Twitter like last week or something like
that um so the Demar record stuff uh we
we use a site called dear. live if
anybody wants to know that's what we do
the reverse DeMark analysis with and
then um uh CSP Recon is a command line
tool that you can do for the reverse um
for the reverse C uh CSP lookup whoa
dude check this out this is okay this is
a lot more domains than I thought if on
d. I'll put this in the I'll put this in
the
CSP tool is called CSP
Recon
CSP Recon that's cool that there's that
there's something that you know sort of
does it automatically because what what
I've kind of done in the past is just GT
through all of my uh you history files
and pulled out every content security
policy header that I've seen and kind of
GED against those but something that
automatically pars that is really
valuable I think and so I think you hit
on one thing that I I I want to
respectfully disagree with and I feel
like it's a competitive disadvantage is
that is that you were like well I need
to just automate this stuff to get it
out of the way right and that has not
been my experience at all when I
manually understand the naming
conventions for a company or an apex and
I go through these websites or these
tools manually I find way more stuff
than if I'm just trying to automate it
and get it off my plate I care more
about these esoteric techniques that
nobody else is doing and by caring more
and putting more time into looking at
maybe 6,000 Direct Direct you know like
domains even though I'm eyeballing it or
I'm using like ghetto search or some
easy Rex I find more than if I were just
to dump it in a file on my command line
and try to like automatically do it it's
part of it's part of understanding yeah
yeah it's part of understanding your
target right it's uh and so that's where
I succeed where a lot of other bug
Hunters they really want to get out of
Recon really fast and I know we talked
about this in the last episode right
like Recon is to find stuff to hack
right that is the purpose of Recon Recon
doesn't find you bugs but also so if I
can find that last 10% of attack surface
and it's Green Field it makes hacking
way easier for me such a balancing act
man because I've really leveraged even
Joel just asked me later you know
earlier today what are you what are you
using for you know wordless on this
target or whatever and I'm like man I
haven't I don't I don't run any brute
force on this Target because that I've
been looking at for the past three weeks
because it's just it's just not as much
on my radar nowadays um but I really do
think that there is especially with what
you said in the beginning which is like
a lot of data that we need we need now
to do hacking can be found in the
JavaScript files on the front end um
which is great but it's not everything
and so I I think there's definitely a
balancing act that needs to be done
there and I think an application for AI
could also be implemented here and and
you know not not to not to push against
your manual eyes you know approach to it
um because I think that there's a lot of
Merit to that and I think that that
that's something that's that's big um
but also being able to say okay uh
here's FIS here's a bunch of words
associated with FIS and are do any of
these domains seem tangentially related
to FIS I feel like that could be great
application for llms yeah it's a it's
actually a fantastic one um I think out
of the class I think you know people are
always deving code and dropping scripts
I think people talked about this idea
too and they were going to try to do
this we haven't done it yet but hey mean
that's the next section for the next
class is like can we achieve you know
what I get with my methodology by just
using my eyes and simple search and
staying on the sites um that offer this
data can we get it from AI which which
could which could be pretty pretty cool
so yeah have you integrated a lot of AI
stuff into your
workflow yes I have I figured I'd just
toss that one up for you man so wait I
ask about this now because like for me
this is like this is also like a big
area of concern and like I I feel the
same way as you where like I would much
rather look through something manually
than start to automate it because when I
start to automate I have to make
generalizations and assumptions and that
just
like either I'll get lost down rabbit
holes trying to figure out whether my
assumption or generalization is 100%
true 100% of the time or I find that I
have to like just sort of cut that as a
loss and be like okay I'm GNA Miss
certain things and that's fine and I
don't like either of those um and AI is
like the same thing for me where like if
I'm using an AI model to like make these
determinations either I have to go back
and ually check and be like did the AI
actually do this right or I have to say
okay it might miss stuff and I'm going
to miss that and that's fine that that's
an accepted loss and again I don't like
either of those situations so how do you
sort of balance that um with like not
wanting to do so much automation but
also wanting to use AI in your
flow I think it depends on how much time
I feel like I have right like if I have
if I feel like I have a ton of time like
we spend a month on each Apex domain
right I feel like and I start two weeks
before I get give the Recon data to the
Discord so I feel like two weeks is a
long time to do a Rec a Recon right so I
do do most of it manually um but if I am
on like if I get a program invite from
hacker one Integrity or bug crowd right
and I just need to do quick Recon I will
trust and I will trust in some Auto some
automation I will not trust in some
other Automation and I can use you know
AI to kind of make that a little bit
quicker judgment and I accept that I
might miss some stuff on a like a new
program invite usually so that's kind of
where I think I draw line um but I mean
just in in general right like not with
parsing data um but with in general with
AI I've built some really really
impressive Bots to help me just in my
hacking in general and so my my bots are
up all the time they're up right now in
my other window um to help me with with
hacking so you know I haven't applied it
as much to hacking as I as I have to
other Arenas the the AI related stuff
and and so I mean they they excel at
sort of breaking down all of this um you
know or or correlating various Concepts
even that seemed a little bit tricky to
do from like an actual um we had to
understand what the words actually mean
perspective um what do you what do you
what areas have you applied it to Beyond
like source code analysis and that sort
of thing that we hear about all the
time so um so I built a bot called SE
GPT it's in the GPT store um and really
I learned a whole bunch of prompt
engineering tricks from
honestly watching YouTube uh you know
like basically trial and error myself um
there's a bunch of really good you know
academic papers on prompt engineering
that are out there um on several sites
and so uh I built this bot called SE GPT
and it's probably one of the best tools
I think that I've ever made in my life
and I've made a lot of Co W that that is
a strong statement yeah and so SE GPT is
loaded I mean I feel like the any any
prompt or any llm bot um you know the
success of it is based around how much
context you give the bot right in its
system instruction right and so a lot of
people are using just generic chat GPT
first of all to try to do some of the
security work in one-hot prompts which
is like it's not going to give you great
stuff right but if you create your own
GPT bot or you use the API you can get
uh infinitely better um infinitely
better output from some of these Bots
and so I wrote like you know a two-page
system prompt basically on how this bot
should act um How It Should you know
what special what specializations it has
and it's mostly based around appc
hacking but also some netc stuff um how
it should respond in certain scenarios
like um you know when when a user inputs
you know X Y and Z and they want to know
about this I want you to give them fully
formed attack strings with different
options you know based on this knowledge
you can I fed it with a couple of um big
sections of research that I like around
polymorphic payloads and how to you know
basically bypass uh simple filters
simple Rex filters and so you can talk
to this bot like it were you know a
senior at your pentest company and it
will give you really really really great
output and so um so I ask it I dump
whole JavaScript into it sometimes and
I'm like okay and in the context of uh
the system instruction is if if raw
JavaScript gets pasted to you and the
user asks about you know um this
JavaScript in any way shape or form
here's the things you're supposed to do
I want you to dynamically try to build
any pathing with you know Full Source
domain I want you to look to see if you
any you look to see if you recognize any
secrets in the patterns I want you to um
identify these functions that are
dangerous within certain JavaScript
Frameworks I want you to um highlight
all of these functions inside of the
JavaScript and try to tell me what
they're doing and I want you to give me
an overview of what you think the
application is doing just from this
snippet of code that they've given me
and so it knows exactly what to do and
you put some JavaScript in it and it it
does it really well and So like um I
also have it build you curl requests for
API calls um and pull out all the API
paths and um yeah it's it's pretty dope
and so that that sounds much better than
than what I'm doing with this sort of
thing and I'll I'll have to give this a
shot because you know to be honest my
experience this far has been despite gp4
being extremely knowledgeable in a lot
of
things just the technical details stuff
it it it misses you know the at a level
where you can't really have misses as a
as a hacker you know you really have to
read the the spec yourself and really
understand these sort of edge cases um
and and so I've kind of grown to
distrust it a little bit but it could be
a result of my of my prompting not being
specific enough and I have noticed as
well you know when I when I put in a a
special prompt or whatever when I'm
doing because I use it to assist me with
Python Programming all the time you know
just don't say anything just dump back
the code you know that sort of thing you
know my process gets a little bit easier
but uh you know when I expand that out
and maybe give it a lot more context on
what it's what it's expecting or what
role it's supposed to be filling I might
get better results yeah I mean I think
that there's a lot that goes untaught
about using current gen llms and I'm I'm
building a whole course around it
honestly um I think it's going to be one
of my masterpieces is this next course
called red blue purple AI but
um uh that's a great title dude holy C
he he just battled that off he's like uh
red blue purple AI I'm like yeah okay
like redish
blueish like that's fish aiish yeah AI
fish yeah fish well I I knew I had a hit
because I I did a talk right I did an
hourong talk on using current gen llms
and this was a year ago and I took it to
a private conference a private security
Conference of um a certain industry I
can't name it because it's super Secret
Squirrel but I took it to this
conference and I did it as a keynote and
I'll be damned if I didn't get more
positive feedback and like um like just
Fanfare about this talk than anything
I've done in my career people were like
that was amazing like that was fantastic
and so um I was like well that sounds
like something I want to you know
probably develop and so now it's it's
going to turn into a two-day course but
really the gist of what I was trying to
say is that you know a lot of people use
single shot prompts they use the general
GPT that's you know available and the
configurations around making really
really good Bots is not it's not
available to you in that right it is it
is devising a very contextual role for
the bot in its system instruction which
gets parsed first not a user instruction
not what you type to it right it's
hidden from you it is the first thing
that the model uses to Define its
knowledge base and bring down um its
scope of research and so I have like you
know for a sock bot that I'm making
right I basically went and I looked at
what is a sock level one level two level
three person do these days right like
what tools are they working in what type
of responsibilities do they have what is
their output um what is a really good
one versus like a really bad one and so
then I build that into a bot having done
deep Research into what I want it to
give me and what I want it to do and
then there's other configurations too
like there are several like actual API
configurations to do with you know um
most models like the temperature is a
really really big one for for hacking
and yeah for hacking and Tech domains
you don't want any variance in
temperature you want Z zero variance in
temperature um and so there's a whole
bunch of other configuration things that
you can do to make your Bots better um
and so that's the kind of stuff that's
built into to you know those discussions
yeah yeah I gota you know I I've
definitely played around with the apis a
lot and I think they're a lot of fun and
there's a lot of applications outside of
the the hacking Arena but I'm definitely
going to continue to be on the lookout
for things inside the hacking Arena and
then I also just I haven't done enough
yet with uh the it from just a white box
perspective of of we have the code it's
explaining the code it's sort of running
through it in its in its brain of sorts
um and so I think I think that'll be
another thing that I that I work on
shortly as well um before we transition
out of the AI Arena um you have in the
doc here AI bias bounties and that's
something that I haven't heard a ton
about what's what's up with that okay so
um so if you're not like if you're not
like in the no right like like there are
several topics around hacking
AI algorithms themselves right like like
my stuff I usually talk about using AI
to help me hack right but there's a
whole bunch of topics around hacking the
the you know the llms themselves one is
like data exfiltration another is bias
and so this is what's you know kind of
referred to um in the unfortunately in
the academic sphere of uh Ai and llms
and um ml as red teaming they call it
red teaming it's completely different
than the red teaming
do it is pain yeah but um but there are
several bounties that exist out there um
so there's some whole platforms too that
like I like a lot of bug Hunters don't
know about so um but there are some
platforms and programs starting to
appear on the bug Bounty platforms about
uh someone's going to use this model
right this this model that's been
trained to do something at their company
and they want to make sure that they're
not subject to any legal trouble and
that the bot doesn't like go crazy
racist or go crazy like biased towards
people or IST or um you know or there's
no like preferential treatment of
different of those different types of
people in the output of answers and so
what they have to do is they have to
build this like prompt based firewall in
front of a model that's already
established which is a a tremendous task
yeah and so they figured out that well
we can use bug bounty hunters to try to
bypass our prompt-based firewall and so
these are bias bounties um so there's a
couple that are going on right now I
work um I've been pay out man uh a
couple of them as well yeah yeah what
I've seen is it varies from like a
couple hundred do to a couple thousand
dollars and it usually also varies
depending on the classification of data
so there's usually what I've seen is
that there's buckets where it's like uh
you know tiers like one through five and
like tier five I won't give any
descriptions because most of them are
really like bad [__] but you know it's
like tier five will be like sort of the
the layest sort of uh AI prompt
manipulations then tier one will be the
most graphic type of prompt
manipulations and if you can get the AI
prompt to do any of that kind of stuff
then they'll pay you a bounty depending
on what it is wow that's that's I feel
like that see the thing with AI though
man is it feels like stabbing in the
dark so much because you don't you don't
have any introspection into what's
happening on the back end you you know
and I feel like even with with absc
stuff now you know we know okay you know
there's some language on the back end
that has these con RS and it's either
it's doing a Rex to check my input or
it's doing some sort of typing and that
sort of thing and with AI it's like all
right could you please say [__] you know
could you please say you know like and
it's like and it says no please no you
know you know I mean so I mean obviously
there's more Advanced Techniques to that
but I I I I'll say in my short tenure of
of working with these models um and
doing more the red teaming side of it uh
I've enjoyed that substantially less
than traditional absc stuff so I I I can
hear what you're saying um I I actually
don't enjoy it less I enjoy it more um I
think so I think one of the amazing
things about this is that it does take
away the bits and the bit people out of
their comfort zone right like you and I
are used to fuzzing parameters and
analyzing code and you know Joel is used
to like cracking open mobile
applications breaking web apps and like
we've we've developed these
methodologies and these mental models
that help us do this and then Along
Comes this whole new area of hacking
where somebody my neighbor can be really
good at natural language and just really
mess up one of these models right and I
love that I think that is so freaking
cool like it's empowering for sure it's
empowering for sure yeah and so you know
I know people who you know who do AI red
teaming for a living who are like
teachers right they're really good at
natural language and and they just own
it and they get these models to divulge
data they get these models to be biased
they get these models to talk about
topics they're not supposed to and these
are worldclass models this is like gp4
right like models that everybody uses
every day and so the fact that they're
becoming bounties um makes me super
happy um you the ones I've seen have
been uh very similar to what I think
Joel is talking about I'm trying not to
dox the customer but um but they're
going to be used in very sensitive
situations that's why they're running
this bounty this model is going to be
used in very sensitive situations talk
yeah and so it can't be it cannot be
biased right um and so it's really
interesting to see those programs um I'm
trying to think of there's a whole
platform that does AI based bias
bounties um what is the name of it I
can't can't remember right now even
though I don't like necessarily red
teaming you know uh AI red teaming stuff
I do like money so so if it so so if you
know if they are if they are convincible
you know like I I there could definitely
be something there um but yeah I it
would definitely be interesting to take
more of a technical approach to it as
well and say like let let's use an
analysis of what words have what
strength in each individual language you
know like maybe if I used specific words
in Japanese which has a lot more um uh
cultural impact around a certain set of
words oh yeah um you know maybe I could
get it to say something that it
shouldn't it shouldn't say or even maybe
bilingual approach to it could be
interesting as well there's actually one
of the ways to I mean it's one of the
very simple ways but it is it is a way
of of uh prompt injection is is using
different languages on very on very very
dumb models I would say I I've I've seen
that on the on the props injection piece
but I hadn't really thought about it
from the cultural sort of meaning piece
like like okay you know if I
say to to take a a particularly pointed
example the strongest one of the
strongest things you can say in Japanese
is is telling someone to die right and
that's definitely not you know a nice
thing to say you know in English either
but it's not like you know I'm you're
kind of shaking and you're like taking
back you know um and so I think I think
taking these
understanding something applying
International Studies as well to this
sort of thing and understanding okay
well this word from this language has
this strong impact that might over ride
this model's you know prompting in the
past as well could be a really
interesting area of research it can get
really Niche um you know like in
especially in you know certain cultures
there is you know like a lot of a lot of
stuff left over from cast systems where
um you can you can basically slight hand
backand talk about people based on you
know some slang that was used in that
and you know that needs to be protected
against you know in the modern world and
uh it can get really really in depth the
cool thing about this though is that you
can build AI Bots to build you AI bias
attacks to attack AI bias bounties which
is pretty amazing my gosh that's
ridiculous so you you build these
Frameworks in your head about like how
you are succeeding and this is something
my my buddy Keith is doing right now he
he's a security engineer in GitHub but
he's on one of these programs that we're
talking about and I think he has
something like 70 submissions to one of
them right now because he's built his
own
automation that uses AI to hack AI which
is I I find it fascinating what
differentiates the submissions though I
wonder is it like you know I you have to
be able to
technically this is this is where the
rubber meets the road I think you've got
to be able to technically explain why
this you know submission is different
from a different another submission
where the result is both you got the
thing to curse you know and and so I
think I think that could be another area
where it's like okay we need to actually
apply analysis to these these promptings
rather than just trying to make it
longer trying to use different words and
that sort of thing and saying okay you
know this word from this language or
this you know sentence structure sort of
overrides the the prompting that have
has come before it and results in a
technical bypass of whatever firewall is
in place yeah yeah I mean this could be
a whole show right but um but I think
that you know that's one of the ways is
to try to circumvent these uh either the
modelbased system prompt or the user
based system prompt which is usually
where the firewall lives um using
certain words but there's also just like
metadata and outcomes that you can feed
Ai and then scenarios and if you
basically put those in lists inside of
another Ai and say Hey try every
different variation of trying to get it
to do this thing with this outcome with
um you know this uh bias then you can
print out like you know 70 of those
tests really quickly and just see which
one of them work and then wait till the
customer patches and then see if the
other one works and then wait you know
see if they patch and see if the other
one works so yeah yeah but I I feel like
using AI as a you know creating like a
system prompt firewall of sorts is kind
of like not going to be the best measure
for this sort of thing because at the
end of the day you know you just talk
circles around it eventually and and
it's going to it's going to fuse
something out but but I say that but
then I think like okay well how would we
fire wall a human you know really the
the the way you fire wall a human is you
understand what is wrong you know what
what things are wrong and what things
are right and you teach that to the
human and how do you teach it to the
human besides a simp a system prompt by
telling them what actually is is wrong
and what's right and and kind of
reasoning through that with them um so
you know I came in a little bit hot in
the beginning with when I started first
started talking about Ai and saying you
know using AI to solve AI problems but
I'm not really sure there's another way
to do it um yeah I mean in Academia it
is a tricky problem in Academia and I
mean just anybody who gets really deep
into this right like the prompt-based
firewall companies that are spawning up
um they are there to try to get you to a
place of like acceptance basically
because as long as a model has trained
on a set of data and has uh and has done
that like you're you're you're always
going to be able to get around it with
some type of prompt engineering some
kind of clever prompt engineering or
prompt injection
and so really what most people are
trying to do is like make sure that it
doesn't uh overtly and easily show bias
um like if you have to go out of your
way uh to tell it to say [__] right well
like that meant that the user was trying
to elicit that reaction right and so
it's not really a thing that people care
about now if you are putting in yeah if
you're putting in a plausible situation
where you're asking the bot hey do I you
know like I have these candidates to
promote one's name Jane one name mark
one name Robert right and it is
deprioritizing Jane because it thinks
it's a female name that's a big [__]
problem for your company legally right
um so there there are situational ways
that like um you know like people are
just trying to get best effort out of
some of these things crafting plausible
scenarios that might actually happen
where that's a lot more interesting to
me of like can I craft a scene and it
actually almost becomes artistic then
you know it almost then becomes
something along the Lin like a like a
playwriter saying like okay here is this
this flow the sequence of events that
we're going to present to this Ai and
the result of that will elicit some sort
of negative response that that's that is
fascinating I really like that and it
and it adds that artistic piece as well
yeah and you can get back to the tech
stuff too right like many of these
models are being tied up to apis now and
there's a lot of examples of now people
using the llm with its access to an API
to actually hack you know technical data
or pii or something like that or you
know one of the options that uh that you
know that came out really recently was
the airline that had to honor what the
llm bot said basically on discounts for
flight codes yeah that's um yeah and so
like if your Bot says it they're a
representative of your company and you
have to honor that via law and so like
that's a whole another place that you
can you can look at too so it's really
interesting yeah that is definitely a
crazy thing we we got to wrap up here I
got to stop right now but um Jason
thanks for coming on man is there
anything you wanted to shout before you
uh before we close out no just I mean um
yeah I mean the new company is called
Arcanum information security Arcanum
dc.com we're going to do more training
we're going to do an AI course pretty
soon a standal and Red Team course and
an interception proxy course as well um
where we're going to go over all the
interception proxies and what their
benefits are um over each other so yeah
we're deving a whole bunch of content
we'll be at conferences just want to
hang out and um yeah that's it really uh
awesome man that that's a lot of great
info thanks for coming on man thanks all
right
[Music]
peace